Guide to the Land Resources Committee records, 1983-1992 UA.03.02.0009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Land Resources Committee records
1983-1992
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of the President. Land Resources Committee
UA.03.02.0009
6.5 Linear Feet
The Land Resources Committee was formed by President Brodie in order to develop and recommend a long-range blueprint for the use of the University's non-campus land holdings. Collection contains the final report and recommendations of the Land Resources Committee, along with the records of the committee and its subcommittees. The collection ranges in date from 1983-1992, bulk 1986-1989.
3,500 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Land Resources Committee records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1992, 1998.
Historical Note
Following a 1987 Urban Land Institute report on the status of the University's non-campus land holdings, the Land Resources Committee was formed by President Brodie in order to develop and recommend a long-range blueprint for the use of these assets. The committee, charged on 24 June 1987, included members of the Board, faculty, student body, and community, and worked through subcommittees that addressed academic and non-academic uses and community concerns. The LRC was chaired by trustee Anthony D. Duke, and submitted its final report in the Spring of 1989.
Collection Overview
Collection contains the final report and recommendations of the Land Resources Committee, along with the records of the committee and its subcommittees. The files include the charge to committee, agendas, minutes of meetings, files on public forums, samples of media coverage, consultants' reports and copies of interim and final reports. The subcommittee records include Academic Uses (the bulk), Non-Academic Uses, Ad Hoc, and Community Concerns. The types of material present include correspondence, maps and plats, video and audio recordings of public forums and a radio broadcast (Duke Forest Dilemma, WUNC, 22 August 1988), reports, and clippings, questionnaires, and proposals. The collection ranges in date from 1983-1992, bulk 1986-1989.
Related Material
Dale B.J. Randall papers 1963-2006.
.University Archives, Duke University.
Duke Management Company records, 1980-1993.
University Archives, Duke University.
Universities and colleges -- North Carolina -- Durham; Land use -- North Carolina -- Planning; Forest management -- Research -- North Carolina -- Durham; Forests and forestry -- Research -- North Carolina -- Durham; Forests and forestry -- North Carolina -- Departmental areas -- Planning; Duke University -- Planning; Duke University. Land Resources Committee; Duke Forest (Durham, N.C.)
- Container List, 6 boxes
  - Academic Subcommittee I, Table of contents, schedules, etc. (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 8 April 1988 (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee I.A, Minutes 1988 January 15-April 29 (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee I.A, Minutes, 1987 September 2-December 13 (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee I.B, Minutes, 1987 September 2-December 13 (Abstracts) (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee II. A-B, Correspondence and memoranda (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee III.A, Duke Forest Management Documents (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee III.B, Duke Forest Research Projects (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee III.C, ULI Report, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee III.D, Maguire/Students report on Duke Forest (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee III.E, Origins and Early History of Duke Forest (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee III.F, Maps (Box 1)
  - Academic Subcommittee V.A-C, Research and teaching potential (Box 2)
  - Academic Subcommittee V.D., Institutional structure (Box 2)
  - Academic Subcommittee V. E-H, Proposals: Arboretum, Conference Center, etc. (Box 2)
  - Report and Recommendations of the Land Resources Committee, Final Report, Spring 1989 (Box 2)
  - Report and Recommendations…, 24 February 1989 (Box 2)
  - Academic Priorities for Duke Forest. Report of the… 31 May 1988 (Box 2)
  - Wallace Roberts and Todd, Duke Forest Master Plan WRT Working Paper no. 2, 11 October 1988 (Box 2)
  - Wallace Roberts and Todd, Duke Forest Master Plan WRT Working Paper no. 2, 3 November 1988 (Box 2)
  - Report and Recommendations of the… 9 December 1988 (Box 2)
  - "Academic Priorities for Duke Forest" Report, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Academic Subcommittee, 1987 [from binder 1] (Box 3)
  - Academic Subcommittee, 1987 [from binder 2] (2) (Box 3)
  - Academic Subcommittee, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Articles, 1987-1989 (3) (Box 3)
  - Charge to committee (Box 3)
  - Consultants - LRC, 1988 (2) (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Tony Duke with LRC, 1987-1989Correspondence, miscellaneous 1985-1989 (Box 3)
  - Community Concerns, 1987-1989 (4) (Box 3)
  - Durham 2005 Comprehensive Plan (Box 3)
  - Final Reports, December 1988 (2) (Box 3)
  - Final Report, Response, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Interim Reports (2)
    - WRT Working Paper, October 7, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Duke Forest Working Paper, no. 2, October 11, 1988 and November 3, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Local Government Interactions re: LRC, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - LRC Materials (Box 3)
  - LRC Meetings
    - August 21, 1987 (Box 3)
    - October 30, 1987 (Box 3)
    - November 6, 1987 (Box 3)
    - February 25, 1988 (Box 3)
  - LRC Meetings, con't. (Box 4)
    - April 8, 1988 (Box 4)
    - May 5, 1988 (Box 4)
    - June 9, 1988 (Box 4)
    - August 19, 1988 (Box 4)
    - September 22, 1988 (Box 4)
    - November 3, 1988 (Box 4)
    - December 8, 1988 (Box 4)
    - February 16, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989-1992 (Box 4)
  - Non-Academic Uses Subcommittee, 1987-1989 (Box 4)
  - Orange County Master Recreation Plan Group, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Public Forum, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Report of Ad Hoc Subcommittee, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Reports and Recommendations, 1988, 1989 c.1 (Box 4)
  - Reports and Recommendations, 1988, 1989 c.2 (Box 4)
  - Revised Final Report, February 24, 1989 (includes black and slides) (Box 4)
  - SFES Board of Visitors, Recommendations, 1986-1988 (Box 4)
  - U.C. General Administration, 1987-1989 (Box 4)
  - Working File (Box 4)
  - Land Resources Committee, Academic Subcommittee (Box 5)
    - Articles, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Base Map (Box 5)
    - Committee Documents, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Land Resources Committee Documents, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Subcommittee Documents Environmental Elements Corp., 1988 (Box 5)
    - Committee Documents: TJOG (Triangle J. Council of Governments) letter, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Community Concern Committee, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Table of Contents - Weekly Updates, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Consultants: Jerry Franklin (Box 5)
    - Consultants: Clark Binkley, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Consultants Trawick Ward, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Consultant Search, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Comments on Orange County Land Use Plan, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence Subcommittee letters and memos, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence Charges to the Subcommittees, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Data History--Frankel, Rachel, "The Couch Tract of the Durham Division of the Duke Forest: A History of Agricultural Land-Use Patterns, 1750-1950." (Box 5)
    - Duke Forest - Annual Report, 1983/1984 - 1985/1986 (Box 5)
    - Data Research--Harvard Forest Models (Box 5)
    - Data Research--Raup, "View from John Sanderson's Farm: A Perspective for the Use of the Land." (Box 5)
    - Data Research--Taylor, Karen J., "Survey of Records on the Duke Forest and the Forestry School, "1986 (Box 5)
    - Data, Maps (Box 5)
    - Data, Other Arboretums, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Data, Silvicultural Demonstration Areas (Box 5)
    - Data Research, Lynn McGuire Letters, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Data Testimonials, Letter from Robert D. Sutter, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Data Testimonials, Letter from Audobon Society, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Data, Urban Land Institute (ULI) Study--Complete Briefing Report, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Data, ULI Short Briefing Report, June 1986 (Box 5)
    - Draft Summary of Recommendations, May 5, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Draft maps (including other subcommittees)
      - Blackwood Division Maps (Box 5)
      - Dailey Tract Maps (Box 5)
      - Durham Division Maps (1) (Box 5)
      - Durham Division Maps (2) (Box 5)
      - Durham Division Maps (3) (Box 5)
      - Eno Division Maps (Box 5)
      - Haw River Division Maps (Box 5)
      - Hillsborough Division Maps (Box 5)
      - Korstain Division Maps (Box 5)
    - JFR's (John F. Richards) notes (Box 5)
    - Long-term Research Sites (draft) (Box 5)
    - Memoranda, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Agendas, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Schedules, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Minutes-Original Notes, 1987-1988 (2) (Box 5)
    - Report Arboretum Minnesota Arboretum Materials, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Report Arboretum letter from William Louis Culberson, Hugo L. Blomquist Professor and Chairman, 1984, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Natural Heritage Proposals, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Report Structure DUPAC-Center for Living, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Report Arboretum letter from Simons-Primate Center, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Report Community Access National Heritage Society, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Report Conference Center "Randall's Thoughts on a Duke Forest Conference Lodge," 1988 (Box 5)
    - Report Structure, Tax Status Examples, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Teaching, Research Questionnaires #1, 1985-1988 (Box 5)
    - Teaching, Research Questionnaires R and T Questionnaires #2, 1986-1988 (Box 5)
    - Teaching, Research Questionnaires R and T Questionnaires #3, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Testimonials, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Draft Reports Change/Comments #1, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Draft Reports Changes/Comments #2, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Draft Reports Changes/Comments #3, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Initial Section: Drafts, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Interim Draft to Subcommittee, 18 May 1988 (Box 5)
    - Draft Report to LRC 31 May 1988 (Box 5)
- Audio/Visual Materials, 1 boxes
  - Audio Cassette, Community concerns, Jonathan Howes (Box 6, Audio-cassette UA0302009-CS-0001)
  - Audio Cassette, "Duke Forest Dilemma" Broadcast: August 22, 1988, Fay M. Henderson, producer (Box 6, Audio-cassette UA0302009-CS-0002)
  - Audio Cassette, Community Concerns, April 21, 1988 (Box 6, Audio-cassette UA0302009-CS-0003)
  - Audio Cassette, Duke Forest Public Hearing, January 30, 1988, 3 tapes (2 copies) (Box 6)
  - Audio Cassette, unmarked (Box 6)
  - Slides, Slide Presentation for Final Land Resources Committee Report, February 1989 (Box 6)
  - VHS cassette, "Tony Duke's copy" (Box 6)
- Oversize
  - Duke Forest Maset Plan, WRT Working Paper: Inventory, Analysis and Land Use Options, August 19, 1988 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Land Classification Process, Consultants - LRC (Oversize-folder 1)